That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 8: Inherited Will
Slime-san...
（シズ）スライムさん
（シズ）ありがとう
Thank you.
（シズ）私は また…
I nearly...
大切な人を
殺してしまうところだった
killed someone I cared about again.
この手で
With my own hands...
Hey, Slime-san...
ねえ スライムさん
聞いてくれるかな？
Would you mind listening?
You shouldn't talk too much...
（リムル）
あんまり しゃべらないほうが…
私という人がいたって
覚えていてほしい
I want people to remember my
story... and know that I lived.
（リムル）分かった
All right.
So Shizu-san told me what happened,
though her recollection was vague.
（リムル）
シズさんは朦朧(もうろう)としながらも
何があったかを語ってくれた
召喚され
イフリートを憑依(ひょうい)させられたこと
She spoke of how Ifrit possessed
her after she was summoned,
友達を殺(あや)めてしまったこと
and how she ended up killing her friend...
And...
そして…
（シズ）ピリノが死んで
After Pirino died,
私は魔王の側近として仕え続けて…
I continued to serve the
Demon Lord as his closest aide.
でも 出会えたの
But then I met...
Met who?
（リムル）誰に？
（シズ）勇者
The Hero.
（リムル）勇者？
Hero?
Yes... The Hero.
（シズ）そう… 勇者
There was a battle,
（シズ）
戦いがあって 魔王は城を捨て
and the Demon Lord abandoned his castle,
leaving me behind as the rear guard.
私を しんがりとして残した
炎の精霊であるイフリートの
意思なのか
Was it the will of the fire spirit Ifrit,
それとも 自分の意思なのか
or was it of my own volition?
今でも よく分からない
I'm still not sure.
I can't beat her...
（シズ）勝てない…
The Hero, huh?
（リムル）
勇者か…
I don't suppose it was the same
one who sealed Veldora...
（リムル）
ヴェルドラを封印したのとは
また別の人間なのかな？
I thought I'd be killed instantly...
（シズ）すぐ… 殺されると思った
でも 話しかけてきた
But then she spoke to me.
どうして ここにいるのか
She asked me why I was there,
どうやって生きてきたのか
how I had stayed alive...
魔人である私の話を信じてくれて
I was a majin, and she
believed everything I said.
“もう 大丈夫だよ”って…
She told me, "It's all right now."
（シズ）
私は感情を取り戻した
My emotions came back to me.
Then the Hero took me in...
勇者に… 彼女に保護され…
その仮面は彼女がくれたんだ
She was the one who gave me that mask.
She said it would boost my magic resistance
魔法抵抗を高めて
and help suppress Ifrit,
the spirit dwelling within me.
私の中にいるイフリートを
抑え込めるって…
Hang on a sec.
（リムル）ちょっと待て
By traveling with her,
（シズ）彼女と共に旅をして
I learned about this world,
and I learned magic.
この世界のことや魔法を教わって
Through the power of the mask, I even
learned to use Ifrit's power, to some extent.
仮面の力で イフリートの力も
ある程度ならば使えるようになって
誰かを助けて 戦って…
By helping others, and fighting...
（リムル）
いつしか“爆炎の支配者”と
呼ばれるようになったわけだ
That's how you came to be known
as the Conqueror of Flames.
Well, that was an awesome attack,
all right! You were on fire!
うん すげえ攻撃だったもんな
かっこいいよ！
彼女と一緒に旅をして
I was so happy traveling with her.
うれしくて 幸せだったな
でも…
But...
But?
（リムル）でも？
（シズ）
あの人は姿を消した
Then she disappeared,
私を残して
leaving me behind.
Why?
（リムル）
どうして？
（シズ）
分からない
I don't know.
どうしてだろ？
Why did she?
どうして…
Why...
"I'm certain we'll meet again."
“きっと また会えるから”
あの人は そう言っていた
That's what she said to me.
私は 強くなろうって決心した
I decided to become stronger.
I wanted to help people who were suffering.
苦しんでいる人を助けたいって…
I worked really hard.
結構 頑張ったんだ
何十年もだよ
偉いと思わない？
For decades!
Doesn't that sound impressive?
Yeah, it sure does.
（リムル）ああ 偉いよ
英雄って呼ばれるようになって
People started to call me a Champion...
だけど 私も もう若くなくて
But I wasn't young anymore.
イフリートの制御も
怪しくなってきて…
It was becoming more difficult
for me to control Ifrit.
One wrong step, and I could
unleash Ifrit by mistake.
一歩間違えたら
イフリートを解き放つかもしれない
そう考えると怖くなって
When I thought about that, I got scared.
このままじゃ また 大切な人を…
I knew I could hurt someone
I cared about again...
だから 私は
引退して指導者になった
So I retired and became an instructor.
An instructor?
（リムル）
指導者？
A teacher at a school.
（シズ）
学校の先生
Oh! There are schools here?
（リムル）
ほう！　学校があるのか
Yes, in a place called
the Kingdom of Ingrassia.
（シズ）
イングラシア王国って所でね
It was a school for kids from other worlds.
異世界から来た子たちの…
Kids? So there must be quite a few people
（リムル）
“たち”ってことは
結構いるんだな
who came here from another world, huh?
別の世界から
こっちの世界に来た人間が
スライムさんが言ってた
ゲームのセリフを教えてくれたのも
It was one of them who taught me
that video game line you quoted.
そのうちの一人だよ
"I'm not a bad slime!"
（２人）
“僕は悪いスライムじゃないよ”
楽しかったな…
It was so much fun.
先生！　今日は何をするの？
What're we gonna do today, Sensei?
ええ そうね
今日は何をしようかな？
That's a good question.
What should we do today?
（シズ）
平和な日々だった
Those days were so peaceful.
Some of them eventually went
off on their own and left me...
私のもとを
去っていった子もいたけど
でも グランドマスターに
なった子もいて…
But one of them went on
to become the Grandmaster.
Grandmaster?
（リムル）グランドマスター？
The one responsible for overseeing
all the guilds in every country.
（シズ）
各国のギルドを統括する最高責任者
That sounds like a big deal!
（リムル）
そりゃあ 大したもんじゃないか！
ええ 大したもの
Yes, it is.
私が教えられることは
もうなくなったと思った
So I thought there was nothing
left that I could teach anyone.
そして 寿命が残り少ないのか
And then, possibly because I'm
nearing the end of my life,
イフリートの意識を
抑え込めなくなってきて…
it became more difficult
to suppress Ifrit's will.
思い出したことが
１つだけあったから
There was only one thing I could remember,
旅に出ようって…
so I decided to go on a journey.
（リムル）
思い出したこと？
What did you remember?
My search for the man who summoned me.
（シズ）
私を召喚した男
捜して…
Do you want revenge?
（リムル）復讐(ふくしゅう)したいのか？
I don't know... but...
（シズ）分からないわ　でも…
会って確かめたいことがあったの
There was something I wanted
to find out from him.
だから 私は…
That's why I...
They were such nice people.
本当に いい子たち
ちょっと危なっかしいけど
A little danger-prone, though.
That's true.
（リムル）そうだな
It was so much fun...
（シズ）楽しかった
But now...
でも もう…
ねえ スライムさん
Hey, Slime-san, what's your name?
名前は何ていうの？
Huh? I told you, I'm Rimuru.
（リムル）え？　俺はリムルって…
本当の名前
No, I mean your real name.
Oh...
It's Satoru. Mikami Satoru.
俺は悟(さとる)
三上(みかみ) 悟
I'm Shizue. Izawa Shizue.
私は静江(しずえ)…
井沢(いざわ)静江
ハア…
（リムル）
シズエさん もう眠ったほうがいい
Shizue-san, you should sleep now.
Satoru-san, I'd like to ask a favor.
悟さん
お願いがあるんだけど…
聞いてくれる？
May I?
Of course. Ask me anything.
（リムル）
いいよ　何でも言ってくれ
私を…
Please...
食べて
eat me.
Just like you ate the curse
that had been cast on me.
私にかけられた… 呪い
食べてくれたみたいに
うれしかった
That made me so happy.
I dislike this world...
この世界が… 嫌い
でも 憎めない
Still, I can't abhor it.
まるで あの男のよう
Just like that man...
だから… だから…
So... That's why...
この世界に取り込まれたくない…
I don't want to be absorbed by this world.
最後の… お願い
This is... my last request.
私を…
君の中で眠らせてくれないかな？
Would you... let me rest inside you?
（リムル）いいよ
Okay.
What's the man's name?
男の名前は？
（シズ）レオン･クロムウェル
Leon Cromwell.
Leon Cromwell...
（リムル）レオン･クロムウェル…
最強の魔王の… 一人
One of the most powerful Demon Lords.
What did you want to find out from him?
（リムル）
そいつに何を確かめたかったんだ？
私という人間がいたことを
I just wanted him to acknowledge that I,
this human, had existed... perhaps.
認めさせたいだけかも… しれない
それに もし あの子たちが救われ…
And... if those kids could be saved...
and returned to... their world...
元の… 世界…
（リムル）約束しよう！
I swear to you on the name of
Mikami Satoru... no, Rimuru Tempest,
三上 悟… いや
リムル＝テンペストの名において
that I will make certain the Demon Lord
Leon Cromwell hears your wishes!
魔王レオン･クロムウェルに
きっちりと
あなたの思いをぶつけてやるよ！
（かすかな声で）ありが… とう
Thank... you...
Shizu-san, my destined one...
（リムル）シズさん…
運命の人よ 安らかに眠れ
Rest in peace within me.
俺の中で…
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
ユニークスキル“捕食者”を
使用しますか？
Use unique skill "Predator"?
Yes.
（リムル）イエス
So that she can dream happy dreams forever
and never have to wake from them.
（リムル）
永遠に覚めることなく
幸せな夢を見られるように
There you are! Please don't
leave me behind again!
そこにいたんですね！
もう私を置いていかないで！
ハア ハア…
Mom!
お母さん！
（静江）お母さん！
Mommy!
Mommy...
お母さん…
（エレン）シズさん 大丈夫かな？
Do you think Shizu is all right?
Don't worry about a thing. Rimuru's with her.
（カバル）
心配いらねえって
リムルの旦那がついてんだからよ
That's right. Those potions of his
are miracle workers, remember?
（ギド）そうでやすよ
旦那がくれた回復薬
すげえ効き目だったじゃないですか
Yeah...
Well, what a surprise.
（リグルド）おや これは…
Are you here to visit our patient?
（リグルド）
皆さんも お見舞いですかな？
リグルドさんもっすか？
Are you, as well?
はい
Yes. I was just bringing a change
of clothes for Lady Shizu.
シズ殿の着替えを
お持ちしたところです
Great Rimuru, may I?
リムル様 失礼します
Master!
（ランガ）我が主(あるじ)…
（３人）え？
（リグルド）その お姿は…
That body...
Th-That's... Rimuru?!
（カバル）
そっ その子が… リムルの旦那〜？
I see...
（カバル）そうか…
シズさん 逝っちまったのか
So Shizu passed on.
本当に
リムルの旦那なんでやんすか？
Are you really Rimuru?
There can be no doubt!
間違いありません！
Did you really think I wouldn't recognize
my master just because his body changed?!
（ランガ）見くびるな！
姿形が変わったぐらいで
分からなくなるとでも思うのか！
Uh, no, I didn't mean it that way...
あ… いや そんなわけじゃなくて
It's just, well...
どうにも その…
You look a bit like a smaller Shizu.
なんか
ちっこいシズさんっぽいっつうか…
（リムル）ホントだよ
It's true.
ほれ
See?
Wow!
ふへ〜
見事なもんでやんすね
That's quite remarkable.
（エレン）シズさんを食べたの？
Did you eat Shizu?
イフリートを食べたみたいに…
The way you ate Ifrit?
It was the only burial I could give her.
（リムル）
それが
俺にできる唯一の葬送だったからね
I'm sorry I didn't consult you,
her travel companions, first.
仲間のお前たちに相談もなく
悪かったな
（カバル）いや…
Well...
それがシズさんの望みだったのなら
しかたないさ
If it's what Shizu wanted,
there was no other choice.
Sorry, Eren.
（リムル）
すまんな エレン
割り切れないかもしれないけど…
You probably think this was unreasonable.
No.
ただ 最後に
お別れの挨拶くらい言いたかったな
I just wish I could have said goodbye to her.
Shizu-san said she had fun
traveling with you three.
（リムル）
シズさんは お前たちと旅ができて
楽しかったって言ってたよ
Though she also said you
were a bit danger-prone.
ちょっと危なっかしいとも
言ってたけどな
あっ おい こら！
何だ その目は！
Hey! Why are you looking at me that way?!
（エレン）だってねえ？
（ギド）ああ
Well, you know...
Yeah.
お… お前だって
Well, what about the time you
got caught in that pitfall?!
この前 落とし穴に
はまってたじゃねえか
あれは あねさんが
急に押すからでやす！
That was because Eren pushed me!
Hey! Don't blame me for that!
ちょっと！　私のせいにしないでよ
（エレン）あのときは突然クモが…
（リムル）しんみりするより
A spider landed on me out of nowhere!
This suits them a lot better
than being all sad and somber.
（リムル）
こういうほうが
こいつららしくていいよな
It was Shizu who took the spider off of me.
Shizu even helped us look
for traps from then on.
（リムル）そうだろ？　シズさん
（ギド）あれ以来 シズさんが
Right, Shizu-san?
（ギド）
罠(わな)探し 手伝ってくれやして…
Actually, I'd say they
relied on her too much.
（リムル）
ていうか こいつら
シズさんに頼り過ぎだな
See? It's not just me!
I'm still the leader!
（カバル）やっぱ 俺がリーダー！
We appreciate all your help.
We'll be on our way now.
（カバル）
ホントに世話になったな
そろそろ おいとまするよ
Back to your home country?
（リムル）国に帰るのか？
Yeah, we need to report to the Guildmaster
ああ ギルドマスターに調査結果と
about our findings, and about Shizu.
シズさんのことも
報告しなきゃならんからな
ここのことは
悪いようには報告しないぜ
We won't say anything bad about this place.
リムルさんのことも伝えとくね
We'll tell him about you, too, Rimuru.
If anything comes up,
you can always send for us.
何か困ったことがあれば
頼るといいでやすよ
Thanks. I'll do that.
（リムル）
おう そうさせてもらうよ
旦那 最後に１つだけ
お願いがあるんだけど
There's one last favor we'd like to ask...
What is it?
（リムル）何だ？
もう一度
人の姿になってもらえねえかな
Could you take your human form again?
（リムル）ん？　別にいいけど
Sure, I suppose...
一体 何だ？
So what is it you want?
Thank you so much, Shizu!
（３人）
シズさん！
ありがとうございました！
俺 あなたに心配されないような
リーダーになります！
I'll strive to be the kind of leader
you won't have to worry about!
あなたと冒険できたこと
生涯の宝にしやす！
My time adventuring with you
will be my life's treasure!
（エレン）ありがとう！
（リムル）わっ…
Thank you!
お姉ちゃんみたいって
思ってました！
You were like a big sister to me!
（リムル）
本当に シズさんの最後の旅仲間が
こいつらでよかった
I'm glad Shizu-san's last travel
companions happened to be these three.
By the way, I noticed your
gear is looking rather shabby.
（リムル）
ところで
お前らの装備 ボロッボロだな
That's mean!
（３人）ひどっ！
うおお… 憧れのスケイルメイル！
It's the scale mail I've always wanted!
ちょっ…
このローブ 何なんですか？
Wait! What the heck is this robe?!
It's light, but sturdy... and it's so pretty!
軽い上に頑丈…
ていうか めっちゃきれい！
D-Do we really deserve such fine equipment?
（ギド）い… いいんですかい？
あっしには
もったいないような作品…
牙狼(がろう)の毛皮まで使用されてやすぜ！
It's even lined with Direwolf fur!
They're parting gifts.
Our artisans' best work!
（リムル）餞別(せんべつ)だよ
うちの職人の力作だ！
Artisans?
（ギド）職人？
Yo!
（リムル）お〜い！
（３人）ん？
（カイジン）
力作っつっても
まだ試作品だけどな
Our best work?
They're actually just prototypes.
（ガルム）着心地は どうだい？
How do they feel?
（ドルド）細工は流々(りゅうりゅう)ってなもんだ
It's all about craftsmanship.
Just speak!
（リムル）しゃべれよ！
I'll introduce you. From the right,
this is Kaijin, Garm, Myrd, and Dord.
紹介しよう
右から カイジンにガルム
ミルドにドルドだ
カ… カイジン？　マジで？
K-Kaijin?! Are you serious?!
（エレン）
腕利きで超有名な鍛冶職人の？
The blacksmith who's
world-famous for his skills?!
And Garm, Myrd and Dord...
（ギド）
ガルム ミルド ドルドって…
あのドワーフ三兄弟？
The three Dwarf brothers?!
家宝にします！
ありがとうございます！
I'll make it my family heirloom!
Thank you so much!
I'm so happy!
（エレン）うれしいです〜！
夢のようでやんす〜！
It's like a dream come true!
I guess Kaijin and his buddies are
even more famous than I thought.
（リムル）
俺が思ってた以上に
カイジンらは有名人だったようだな
They're human national treasures...
or is it "dwarven national treasures"?
人間国宝… いや ドワーフ国宝か
After raising a fuss big enough
to blow their sadness away,
（リムル）
悲しみを吹き飛ばすかのように
大騒ぎしたあと
the three of them left.
彼らは去っていった
They're so strong and resilient.
I should learn from them.
そのたくましさを
俺も見習わなければなるまい
The girl who lost everything
to the flames so long ago,
（リムル）
かつて炎で全てを失った少女は
oddly enough, gained the
power of fire in her travels.
世界を渡り
奇(く)しくも炎の力を手に入れた
She used that power to help the people,
少女は その力を
人々を守ることに使ったが
but the flames gradually consumed her
炎は少しずつ彼女を蝕(むしば)み
until, eventually, she could
no longer control them.
やがて少女は
炎を御(ぎょ)することができなくなった
Her name was "Shizue Izawa."
少女の名は シズエ･イザワ
炎の最上位精霊 イフリートを宿し
She was a Champion whose body housed Ifrit,
a high-ranked fire spirit,
earning her the title "Conqueror of Flames."
“爆炎の支配者”と うたわれた
英雄だった
I promised Shizu-san...
（リムル）
シズさんと約束したからな…
Before I can slug the Demon Lord
Leon Cromwell who made Shizu-san cry,
（リムル）
シズさんを泣かせた
魔王レオン･クロムウェルの
横っ面をぶん殴ってやるために
情報を集めなくては
I first need to gather information.
俺は約束を
守る男なのだ
I'm a man who keeps his promises.
（リムル）
こうして なんということもない
普通の人生を歩むはずだった男は
And that's how the man who thought
he had an ordinary, uneventful life
and was stabbed on the street and died,
通り魔に刺されて死亡し
異世界に転生を果たした
was reincarnated in another world,
where he inherited the will of both the Storm Dragon, Veldora, and a human woman,
暴風竜ヴェルドラ
そして
１人の女性の思いと姿を受け継ぎ
giving him new purpose.
目的を得た
He was a slime by the name of Rimuru,
リムルという名の１匹のスライム
そのスライムを中心として
and the world was about to usher in
世界は
激動の時代を迎えることになる
a turbulent, new era, with this
lone slime at the center of it all.
Yeah, this feels much more right.
（リムル）
やっぱり
こっちのほうが落ち着くな
（ランガ）クウン
（魔物）ハア ハア…
（ゲルミュッド）
お前に名前と食事をやろう
I will give you a name and some food.
（魔物）あなたは？
Who are you?
I'm Gelmud. You can think
of me as your father.
（ゲルミュッド）ゲルミュッド
俺のことは父と思うがいい
Would you rather die here?
このまま死ぬか？
Give me a name... and food.
（魔物）名前を…
そして 食事を…
Your name is Geld.
（ゲルミュッド）お前の名はゲルド
（魔物）ゲルド…
Geld...
（ゲルミュッド）
やがてジュラの大森林を手中に収め
One day, you will take possession
of the Great Forest of Jura
and become the Orc Disaster.
オーク･ディザスターとなる者だ
Next time, "Attack of the Ogres."
（大賢者）
次回「大鬼族(オーガ)の襲撃」
Attack of the Ogres